

## SENIOR SOFTWARE ARCHITECT

acordmike@gmail.com 1-920-224-4584 http://www.mikeacord.com

Seasoned application developer and solutions consultant with over 14 years of experience in designing, developing, and implementing database and web applications using Microsoft technologies. Specialties include C#, ASP.Net MVC, SQL Server development and administration and SharePoint deployment, development and administration.

### SKILLS

WEB JAVASCRIPT HTML 5 CSS LAMP MVC REST CSS

**JAVASCRIPT ANGULAR.JS JQUERY BACKBONE.JS** 

DATABASE SQL SERVER TSQL INTEGRATION SERVICES ANALYSIS SERVICES REPORTING SERVICES

**CLOUD AZURE** 

**PROJECT AGILE TFS** 

**DEVOPS TFS TEAM CITY OCTOPUS DEPLOY** 

**SHAREPOINT ADMINISTRATION DEVELOPMENT OFFICE 365** 

### **EMPLOYMENT**

#### Senior Solutions Architect, Consultant, Omni Resources

2012-07 — Present

Senior Microsoft Architect, building solutions for clients

- Led team creating web-based report designer and high-performance report execution engine for a student management system
- Worked on team developing a dealer showcase website in Azure using ASP.Net MVC, web services and Backbone.JS
- Developed new data warehouse for an insurance company using SQL Server, AWS and Redshift
- Developed a flexible interview building and reporting application for a health outcome reporting company
- Managed and administrated internal systems and applications

Agile C# DevOps Javascript ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Analysis Services Integration Services SharePoint Azure Business Intelligence Office365 TFS Administration

#### SharePoint/Business Intelligence Technical Lead / Consultant,

2008-06 — 2012-07

**Heartland Business Systems (Avastone)** 

Designed and developed custom .Net, Business Intelligence and SharePoint solutions for businesses, managed technical consulting team

- Developed school teacher evaluation system in SharePoint, .Net and javascript
- Created health reporting and analytics system in ASP.Net MVC
- Designed and created school district website in SharePoint
- Developed new product workflow application in InfoPath
- Designed and developed a data warehouse on SQL Server database and Analysis Services
- Implemented numerous SharePoint installations, upgrades and custom development projects

C# Javascript ASP.Net MVC SQL Server Analysis Services Integration Services Sharepoint Business Intelligence

#### Business Intelligence Consultant, Fujitsu Consulting

2006-08 — 2008-04

Senior BI Consultant building data integration solutions

- Designed and developed data migration strategy from legacy system using Integration Services
- Created real-time data integration from new web application back to legacy mainframe
- Developed reporting services reports

SSIS SQL Server ASP.Net C# Reporting Services

#### Business Intelligence Consultant, Compuware

2005-05 — 2006-07

SQL Server development consulting

- Developed and optimized SQL Server applications
  Developed bill of materials and reporting applications
- Developed bill of materials cost reporting application in MS Access
- Developed Crystal Reports

SQL Server MS Access Crystal Reports

### Systems Analyst, DRS Power & D

2001-08 — 2005-08

Internal application development and support

- Gathered and analyzed business requirements
- Used application development methodologies to create internal business applications
  Led cross-functional multi-site teams to facilitate and improve business processes
- Led cross-functional, multi-site teams to facilitate and improve business processes
- Created an Operational Data Store from mainframe data and Crystal Reports to the analyze data

SQL Server DTS ASP VB.Net

# EDUCATION

MS in Management-Electronic Business, University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee

2002-08 — 2003-12

**BS in Business and Computer Systems, International Business,** 1998-08 — 2002-05 Milwaukee School of Engineering